sas.com 2015-06-07

# Privacy Statement | SAS

## Our Commitment to Privacy  

Your privacy is important to us. SAS, our subsidiaries and affiliates ("SAS" or "we") are providing this notice to describe and explain our information collection practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

### The Information We Collect and How We Collect It

In general, you can visit this website, and use associated SAS technologies, without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. There are times, however, when we may gather information from you. Personal information like your name, postal address and e-mail address is obtained only when voluntarily submitted. Technical information, like details about your device and IP address, may be collected by virtue of your use of certain other SAS technologies. SAS collects this information in several ways:  

  * Through the SAS Profile page (see below)
  * Through registration, surveys and other online forms (some of which may be managed by third parties on behalf of SAS)
  * As part of an ongoing sales process
  * While providing technical support, consultation, live chat, or product information
  * Through the process of maintaining and upgrading our products
  * Through automated means such as communications protocols, e-mail communications and cookies
  * Through our mobile applications (some of which may be managed by third parties on behalf of SAS)
  * Through your use of social connectors and SAS-affiliated social networking areas
  * Through your interest in SAS ads placed on third party sites

To provide you with timely, high-quality information, we may also ask you to provide us with information regarding your professional interests and experiences with our products or services. Providing us with this information is optional. Personal data or other data collected online may also be combined with information you provide to us through other sources such as product registration, call centers, or in conjunction with events such as trade shows, training seminars and conferences. Information that you supply will relate to the relationship that SAS has with you or your organization.

**Your SAS Profile**  
Your SAS profile is one collection point we use to manage your personal information. You can create, access, and update your profile information at any time by visiting <http://www.sas.com/profile>. Creating a SAS Profile enables you to:

  * Specify your preferences related to SAS' communication with you via e-mail
  * Gain access to restricted site content
  * Access SAS white papers
  * View webcasts and other online events
  * Subscribe to SAS e-news which is delivered to your in-box and targeted to your needs and interests
  * Manage your subscriptions to print and online SAS publications
  * Receive e-mail alerts when key content goes live
  * Auto-populate form fields with personal information when you make online transactions or complete event registration forms
  * Participate in [SAS Communities](https://communities.sas.com/welcome "Links to communities.sas.com")  

**Web Server Logs**  
In the process of administering this site, we maintain and track usage through Web server logs. Web server logs provide information such as what types of browsers are accessing our site, what pages receive high traffic, and the times of day our servers experience significant load. We use this information to improve the content and navigation features of our site. Anonymized or aggregated forms of this data may be used to identify future features and functions to develop for the site and to provide better customer service.

**Cookies**  
Certain technologies, called "cookies," can be used to provide tailored information from a website. A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to your browser, which your browser may then store on your system. Some pages on our site use cookies that assist you in navigating and using the site, for example, to help you access secure areas or use a shopping cart. SAS may set these types of cookies without requesting your consent.

Other pages on the site may set cookies to collect aggregate usage information that we use to improve how the site works. Cookies may also be used on our site to remember certain choices you make, such as your geographical region, your user name, or other personalization or customization. We use these cookies to improve your user experience so we can better serve you when you return to our site. SAS will consider your use of the Web site as your consent for SAS to set these types of cookies.

SAS may work with select third-party partners who set cookies to serve you SAS-related content, including SAS advertisements, on their sites or elsewhere on the Internet, based on your prior visits to our site. SAS also sets cookies that look at your preferences when you use the website so that SAS may offer you tailored marketing collateral, such as whitepapers, that you may be interested in. You may need to enable use of these kinds of cookies via the mechanism provided by SAS for these cookies to work. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. By using our website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your system. For more information, please refer to user information provided with your Web browser. At this time, we do not respond to browser “do not track” signals, but we do provide you the option to opt out of behavioral advertising. To learn more about behavioral advertising or to opt-out of this type of advertising, visit the [Network Advertising Initiative website](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ "External link:  Goes to Network Advertising web site") or [Digital Advertising Alliance website](http://www.aboutads.info/ "External link:  Goes to Digital Advertising Alliance web site"). Please note that if you disable cookies, some site functionality may be limited.

**Web Beacons**  
Some of our Web pages and HTML-formatted e-mail use Web beacons in conjunction with cookies to compile aggregate statistics about website usage. A Web beacon is an electronic image, called a single-pixel (1x1) or clear GIF. Web beacons can recognize certain types of information on a visitor's computer, such as a visitor's cookie number, time and date of a page view and a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed. You may render some Web beacons unusable by rejecting their associated cookies.

**Personalized URL Links and Personalized Message Content**  
Occasionally, we may create a unique web URL link for certain visitors. If you visit one of these sites, you may find forms that are already filled out with your name, or other types of information you have previously indicated an interest in, based on information you have given us before. We may also personalize the content of newsletters, e-mail offers, invitations, or SAS advertisements served to you on our third party partners’ websites, based on topics in which you have previously indicated an interest. We collect information about how you consume this type of personalized information in order to help us provide you with other information that is better tailored to your interests. If you choose to visit one of these personalized web URL links, you are agreeing to allow SAS to collect information about your visits and also to associate that information with other information about you and your relationship with SAS. If you do not wish your information to be used in this way, do not accept the invitation to visit these sites.

**Other Technologies**  
We may use other technologies to capture specific data, such as the pages you view, the items you download, the links you click, your access times, and your Internet Protocol (IP) address, domain name, and system configurations and settings, to help us understand how you use SAS-affiliated technologies, serve you relevant content, and to assist you with questions you may have regarding our products and services. If you decided that you want to fine-tune the information that SAS is providing to you, we invite you to update your [SAS Profile](http://www.sas.com/profile).

### How We Use Your Information

SAS may use your personal information to:

  * Fulfill subscription requests, orders for software and services made online and to provide other information you request
  * Make the website easier for you to use
  * Help us customize content most relevant to your interests
  * Notify you about important news concerning SAS
  * Notify you of new products and services, product updates, technical support issues, events and special offers we think you may be interested in
  * Promote our products and services on our website and third party partners’ websites
  * Prevent and detect fraud or other prohibited or illegal activity
  * Protect the security and integrity of the website

We do analyze some of our Web services such as registrations, demos, downloads, and e-mail responses at the individual level in order to improve the quality of those offerings and to better tailor our marketing to our customers' needs.

### How We Share Your Information

We may share the personal data you provide with other SAS entities and/or business partners for purposes related to those described above. We will not sell, rent or lease to others your personally identifiable information. SAS reserves the right to disclose any and all pertinent information to law enforcement or other governmental officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate.

### Choice / Opt-Out

SAS offers you the choice of receiving different types of communication and information related to our company, products and services. You may subscribe to e-newsletters or other publications; you may also [elect to receive](http://www.sas.com/emailpreferences/optin.html) marketing communications and other special offers from us via e-mail. If at any time you would like to change your communication preferences, we provide unsubscribe links and an [opt-out](http://www.sas.com/emailpreferences/optout.html) mechanism for your convenience. You may also access and manage your preferences from your SAS Profile page.

### Our Commitment to Data Security

SAS is concerned about the security of your information. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. We use encryption technology when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information. Credit card numbers are used only for processing payment and are not used for other purposes.

### External Links

Links to third-party websites from this website are provided solely as a convenience to you. If you use these links, you will leave this site. We have not reviewed these third-party sites and do not control them. SAS does not assume responsibility for any of these sites, their content, or their privacy policies. SAS does not endorse or make any representations about them or any information, software or other products or materials found there, or any results that may be obtained from using them. If you decide to access any of the third-party sites linked to this site, you do so at your own risk.

### Our Worldwide Practices

SAS is a global corporation with subsidiaries and business partners in many countries, and with technical systems that cross borders. Personal information collected on our site may be transferred across state and country borders and stored or processed in the United States or any other country in which SAS, its subsidiaries, affiliates or business units maintain facilities for the purposes of data consolidation, storage, and simplified customer information management. By using this website, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country of residence. SAS, our subsidiaries, affiliates and business units will handle your information collected on our site in a consistent manner, as described here, even if the laws in some countries may provide less protection for your information.  Our privacy practices are designed to protect your personal information all over the world. To ensure adequate protection for the personal information of employees and workers that SAS receives in the United States from the European Economic Area, and personal information that SAS’ Solutions OnDemand business unit receives in the United States from the European Economic Area, SAS has certified to the US-EU Safe Harbor Principles. For more information about the Safe Harbor Principles, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's website at <http://export.gov/safeharbor/>. For more information about the privacy practices of SAS Solutions OnDemand, please see the SAS Solutions OnDemand Business Customer Privacy Policy.

### Changes to This Statement

If there are updates to the terms of SAS' online Privacy Statement, we will post those changes here and update the revision date in this document so that you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it, and what choices you have. Your continued use of SAS' website following the posting of changes to this Privacy Statement means you accept those changes.

### Your Acceptance of These Terms

By using SAS' website, you signify your assent to this Privacy Statement.

### How to Contact Us

Should you have comments or questions about this Privacy Statement, you may e-mail us at: [privacy@sas.com](mailto:%20privacy@sas.com). You may also contact us via postal mail at the following address:

SAS Institute Inc.  
SAS Campus Drive  
Cary, NC 27513  
ATTN: Legal Division / Privacy Officer

_Revised April 14, 2014_
